Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Kneel.
I sent them out because I still want to save you some face.
If they gossip about this you'll have
no burial ground for your dead body.
I don't understand what Your Majesty is referring to.
Do you not?
What wholesome ingredients did you use for the
chestnut cakes you sent to Concubine Sourire?
I did send those to her,
with good intentions.
Was it?
I already asked Dr. Zhang.
They abound with oleander pollen.
Oleander is poisonous.
I didn't know.
Stop lying to me!
Who went to the Infirmary to review
Concubine Sourire's prenatal tonics?
You saw she is taking cassia twig.
What a good plan!
Oleander combined with cassia twig is a good
formula to terminate pregnancy.
You tried to murder an imperial heir!
I was being a fool.
I made a stupid mistake.
You were not stupid.
You deliberately tried to kill Concubine Sourire's child!
Your Majesty!
The Third Prince is my only child.
I have to make plans for his future.
What about his future?
Even if Concubine Sourire gives birth to a prince, he will be an infant.
What are you afraid of?
I have to look ahead.
I have lost His Majesty's favor.
And His Majesty isn't fond of the Third Prince.
If he does not become the crown prince,
he will have no future.
You're being an idiot!
Do you think you're helping him?
Had you killed Concubine Sourire's child today,
do you think His Majesty would forgive you?
Every time His Majesty sees the Third Prince,
he would think of his depraved mother!
Then the third Prince would have no hope.
Your Majesty, I was so stupid!
I was being so very stupid!
Of course you were.
Fortunately Concubine Sourire only reported to me
and I spoke for you.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be kneeling and talking here.
So Concubine Sourire knew?
Of course she did.
She wanted to tell His Majesty.
I persuaded her not to.
I told her that I would impose punishment on you.
So she agreed to go back.
I thank Your Majesty.
But after all, she was not harmed.
She did not eat it.
You had the intent to harm
and acted on it.
The only difference is she didn't consume it
and her pregnancy was not affected.
That is not only her luck, but also yours!
How could the Third Prince have such a stupid mother
who would do something so stupid?
I will make sure it ends up well.
But to keep Concubine Sourire quiet about it,
I have to administer punishment.
The Third prince is not allowed to visit you any more.
Your Majesty!
You are his mother,
and you have to learn this lesson.
I will fill your role and take care of him.
He doesn't need you or the Palace of Eternal Spring.
No. Your Majesty.
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
I cannot live without him.
Don't worry.
I won't cut off the bond between you.
You can come to the Palace of Great Benevolence
whenever you want to see him.
This way, even if more people find out,
I will be able to explain and protect you.
Of course, if you disagree,
Concubine Sourire might magnify the problem and
you would never be able to see the Third Prince again.
I thank Your Majesty.
My Lady, you've had an unpleasant day.
You should go to bed early.
I'm really grateful for Linrong today.
It would have been a disaster had she not detected the oleander.
Lady Lingrong is a thoughtful person.
I thought she was overly emotional and
untrusting so I distanced myself from her.
It's my fault.
Not exactly.
"Only the passage of days reveals the heart of a person".
I heard that Her Majesty imposed
stern punishment on Consort Astuce.
Her Majesty announced that she will
personally look after the Third Prince.
Being separated from a child is so painful for a mother.
Her Majesty has imposed stern punishment on her.
It's all right. Peace in the palace is more important.
I wish this could really bring peace to the palace.
Lady Fuca has had a miscarriage.
I don’t want anything else to happen and worry His Majesty.
I feel like these things happen in a cycle.
The victim today could be the villain tomorrow.
Everyone is harmed and everyone inflicts harm.
It's like an odd circle. It's awful.
The rat race in the palace never ends.
My Lady, all you can do is protect yourself.
I’ve been dwelling on it for two days and I'm still worried.
So I was hoping to talk to you today.
Yes.
It wasn't a fair settlement
and you have to endure it.
Without peace in the harem,
His Majesty can't focus on the court.
The concubines are inextricably intertwined with
the powers at the imperial court.
The Third Prince might even be compromised.
The Fourth Prince and the Fifth Prince are very young.
If this was taken advantage of by some ill-intentioned officials,
I’m afraid the court would again be thrown into chaos.
It was fortunate that Lingrong found out.
Or my child and I would have been harmed.
Attendant An is a careful person.
I will feel more at ease if she can keep you company.
This is a sign to be extra careful in the future.
I will, Your Majesty.
This year has been strange.
I hope we didn't offend any gods.
His Majesty said droughts have been occurring.
Two months have passed without a drop of rain.
This is of particular concern to social stability.
The court is disturbed by Heaven's disasters and
the harem is disturbed by human sorrow.
Your Majesties must be having a difficult time.
His Majesty and I are planning to pray for
rain at the Temple of Heaven
And stay at the Temple of Pure Dew for a few days.
Noble Consort Fleur will be in charge of the palace affairs.
Consort Estime will assist her.
I will stay in my palace and avoid unnecessary trips.
That will be good.
You know what Noble Consort Fleur is like.
You’ll have to be tolerant
and report to us when we come back.
Since you're pregnant,
she won’t be so hard on you.
Try not to worry.
His Majesty and I will return in ten days.
I thank Your Highness for caring.
I will take good care of myself.
Certainly.
How is your scar?
Attendant An gave me her Scar Relief Gel.
I’ve been using it and it has helped a lot.
You should keep using it since it's effective.
I hope it will entirely heal and disappear.
I appreciate Your Majesty's concern.
You're back, Sourire.
You came at a good time. I was just thinking of you.
I'm running out of the the Scar Relief Gel.
I'll have to trouble you to bring me some more.
What a coincidence, I thought of the same.
You see, I’ve bought some with me.
I'm sorry to keep bothering you with this.
I have already used three or four boxes.
But I still need you to make some more.
You are carrying a child. You should sit down.
I’m idle all day.
I'm happy to spend some time making the medicine for you.
You're still recovering from your cough.
Don’t work too hard.
His Majesty the Emperor.
Huan Huan.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
I’ve told you not to move needlessly.
Why would you even bother to bow?
What if you slipped from standing up so quickly?
I’m not that fragile.
How have you been feeling this couple of days?
I often feel fatigued and my back is sore.
But the doctors said these are normal
since I'm pregnant for the first time.
Did Dr.Wen visit you, Sourire?
No. Dr. Wen is busy treating the plague,
and taking care of Meizhuang.
Dr. Zhang is attending to my pregnancy.
Since His Majesty is here to visit,
I will excuse myself.
The Empress and I will go to
the Temple of Heaven to preside at a ceremony.
Noble Consort Fleur will be in charge of the palace affairs.
I know that you are not on good terms with her.
You must be deferential to her at all times.
Tell me your grievances when I'm back - if there are any.
I understand.
Hmm ... More importantly,
You need more rest when you're pregnant.
Try to avoid going to the Palace of Earthly Honor.
I will be cautious. Your Majesty must not worry.
I can't stop worrying.
Shilan is a proud woman.
Her words are harsh.
But she has a good heart.
If Your Majesty is worried,
you should just have fewer concubines.
Even I know it's hard for Your Majesty to
apportion your heart to so many concubines.
If I were not the Emperor,
I would be satisfied with having the Empress as my wife,
and you and Shilan as my concubines.
Noble Consort Fleur.
I entrust you with all palace affairs.
Take good care of the palace.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Lower the sedan chair.
Raise the sedan chair.
Their Majesties depart.
I bid Your Majesties goodbye.
Only Her Majesty is going with His Majesty.
I'm afraid she is praying not only for Heaven's rain.
She will be praying for a prince,
which has always been her wish.
Concubine Sourire, do you agree?
If Her Majesty conceives an imperial heir,
Your Noble Highness will be happy for her.
I certainly will.
And I suppose you will also be happy for her, won't you?
Her Majesty is "the Mother of the Nation".
A child of Her Majesty will be Heaven's blessing to the country.
No one will feel unhappy about it.
You always have a way with words.
Concubine Sourire is pregnant.
She shouldn't be standing here for too long.
She should go back to her palace.
Although you share the authority to assist in the palace management,
a Consort is different than a Noble Consort.
The lack of one word is the lack of superiority.
As such, you must not disobey my orders.
Do you understand, Consort Estime?
Yes.
I have been in His Majesty's service longer than you.
When I was his Lord Consort, you were just
his concubine serving in my chamber.
Even if you are blessed to be
on equal footing with me one day,
you must not forget you were once in my service.
When in my presence, if I haven't mentioned a topic,
that is not the time for you to speak.
Do you hear?
Yes.
The weather's hot today.
We will dismiss.
Here, help her sit down quickly.
Peace to Your Highnesses.
- You may rise.
- I thank Your Highness.
You've come at a good time, Dr. Zhang.
Concubine Sourire doesn't look very well.
Please check on her.
Yes, I'm here for Her Highness's routine pulse-taking.
Your Highness was just out for the morning.
Why does Your Highness look so pale?
I was feeling nauseous standing in the sun.
I feel better now.
My Lady, although you had prolonged
exposure to the sun, it's nothing serious.
But may I ask if you have been feeling disturbed recently, My Lady?
My Lady has been in grief ever since Lady Chun passed away.
My Lady, your child is in good health.
However, being a melancholic mother can be harmful to the child.
I hope you can put your mind at ease.
Thank you, Dr. Zhang.
My Lady, your constitution is vulnerable to the scorching weather.
Please avoid walking in the scorching sun and take more rest.
Thank you for your advice.
Vermilion, please see Dr. Zhang out.
I thank Your Highness.
My Lady, although Dr. Zhang is a prudent person,
I will still show his prescription to
Dr. Wen as we always did.
You must have forgotten that Dr. Wen left with His Majesty.
Dr. Wen checked all Dr. Zhang's prescriptions.
Don't worry.
Yes.
Thank you, Estime.
You didn't have to speak for me.
It's all right.
I heard worse when I was serving in her chamber.
I am already accustomed to that.
But as you have seen,
I might not be able to protect you even if I want to.
Fortunately, His Majesty will be back soon.
I suppose nothing can go wrong.
I appreciate your concern, Estime.
His Majesty and Her Majesty are away,
and the Empress Dowager is unwell.
The palace is now Your Highness's.
It is.
What an opportunity
to take care of the one who needs to be taken care of.
I'm tired.
Light my Pleasancy [incense].
Yes.
My Lady, your prenatal tonic is ready.
I always feel tired no matter how long I sleep.
And I have a back pain.
What happened, My Lady?
It's all right.
It's probably because we have been going
to Noble Consort Fleur's palace every day.
It's taxing.
She likes to summon all the concubines to
sit there and hear her talk for hours.
Isn't she tired already?
She's very pleased with her high status and power.
She expects us to listen to her the way we listen to Her Majesty.
I really dislike the incense she uses.
It smells pungent to me.
Her Noble Highness is fond of
using incense and burns a lot of it.
It only smells good at a distance.
My Lady, you have been feeling exhausted recently.
Would you like some hot water and to rest?
I will tell Xiao-Yunzi to bring Dr. Zhang here.
Go quickly.
Yes.
Peace to Your Highness.
You may rise.
Her Noble Highness requests Your Highness's
attendance to the discussion of palace affairs.
It's not that I don't want to go,
but I'm feeling unwell today.
May I trouble you to extend my apology to Her Noble Highness?
Her Noble Highness is managing the palace
at His Majesty's behest ...
My Lady is not well today!
Her Majesty waived My Lady's daily attendance
because she is pregnant.
And My Lady is ill today.
My Lady doesn't need to go even if Her Majesty summons.
Her Noble Highness understands that
Your Highness has been unwell
so she sent me here to go with Your Highness.
How will Her Noble Highness be able to discuss the
palace affairs without Your Highness's presence?
Her Noble Highness is in charge of
the palace on behalf of His Majesty.
I hope Your Highness will not disobey His Majesty's decree?
I agree, Mr. Zhou.
But I don't feel well today.
I'm afraid I'm not able to make the trip.
Consort Honnête didn't go because of her health.
But all the other concubines have arrived
including Attendant An.
They're all waiting for Your Highness.
My Lady,
shall we wait until we see Dr. Zhang?
I hope Your Highness will leave now.
Her Noble Highness will be upset if you are late.
That's not good for any of us.
You can wait outside.
I'll get changed and go.
Aye, I'll wait for Your Highness outside.
Since Your Highness sent Zhou Ninghai to her palace,
Concubine Sourire will certainly come.
Even the Empress has to respect me.
How dare she not come?
Your Noble Highness doesn't have to do this to her today.
There is plenty of time in the future.
The best time is to take her down is during her prime.
Now that Concubine Sourire is so proud of her pregnancy,
It's time that I give her a lesson.
She will know that under my throne,
they are all merely servants to His Majesty.
No one is to curry favor from His Majesty
or steal His Majesty's favor from me!
Your Noble Highness, all the concubines have arrived.
My Lady, do you really have to go?
His Majesty and Her Majesty repeatedly enjoined me
to be tolerant of her when they left the palace.
If I don't go, I will only bring trouble to myself.
Everyone is there. It will be fine.
Jinxi and I will go with you.
Let's go.
The Empress Dowager has been unwell recently.
Her Majesty was talking about Your Lordship today.
Is Her Majesty feeling better today?
Not really, Her Majesty still coughs at night
and has trouble sleeping.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
-You will wait here. Jinxi will go in with me.
-Yes.
Peace to Your Noble Highness.
I've arrived late because I wasn't feeling well this morning.
I beg Your Highness's pardon.
I understand that your pregnancy causes you to be delicate.
Rise.
The rose cakes smell the most pleasant of all the pastries.
But the smell fades in Your Highness's palace.
May I humbly ask what incense is used
in the Palace of Earthly Honor?
You've got a good sense of smell.
The incense is exclusively provided by His Majesty.
It's called Pleasancy.
Only I have His Majesty's permission to use it.
I feel inferior compared to Your Highness's knowledge and experience.
An, you didn't know about this because you
came into His Majesty's service later than us.
Her Noble Highness was granted exclusive use of
Pleasancy before we moved into the palace.
One of its ingredient is ambergris,
which was rewarded by the prior emperor.
His Majesty used half of it to make
Pleasancy for Her Noble Highness.
That is just an old story. Don't mention it.
My apologies, Your Noble Highness.
Quarrels and fights are common among the servants in the palace.
They will be disciplined since we have more time now.
The servants dare to start quarrels and fights
only because their mistresses are in high status.
"When the top beam is crooked, the entire house is twisted."
Take Lady Fuca for example.
She behaved arrogantly when she gained favor from her pregnancy.
If anyone follows in her footsteps, and
hasn't learned a lesson from her,
it will not be pardoned.
Concubine Sourire,
do you recognize your offence?
I summoned all concubines to discuss palace affairs.
Concubine Sourire arrived late for no reason,
which shows her disrespect for me.
Kneel!
I recognize my fault.
I begged for Your Noble Highness's forgiveness when I arrived.
If you disrespect your superiors already,
how will you behave when you give birth to an imperial heir?
Do you think you will be ruling the harem under your name?
I understand Your Highness is angry,
but I have to say
His Majesty and Her Majesty took good care of Lady Fuca
not because of Lady Fuca's pregnancy
but for the family and the country.
I have explained to Your Noble Highness the reason for my delay.
Although I offended Your Noble Highness today,
the Empress Dowager and the Empress
are the heads of the harem,
so it's upsetting to me when Your Noble Highness
suggests I would ever rule the harem.
Your Noble Highness,
you might be feeling thirsty after this morning's talks.
Would Your Noble Highness like to
have some tea and take a break?
Concubine Sourire is wrong for being late,
but Your Noble Highness should allow her to rise.
Women should obey feminine virtues.
Concubine Sourire from the Zhen family defies her
superior and twists my words to excuse herself.
She will kneel outside my palace and read Lessons for Women
so she will learn her lesson.
Your Noble Highness, the yard is paved
with hard granite and burning under the fierce sun.
Concubine Sourire is pregnant. She can't kneel there.
I beg Your Noble Highness's pardon for Sourire
considering her pregnancy.
Your Noble Highness has the right to punish Concubine Sourire.
But if this harms the imperial heir,
His Majesty and Her Majesty will punish Your Noble Highness.
Discipline must be upheld when it is compromised.
His Majesty and Her Majesty would do the same.
Are you trying to threaten me with Their Majesties?
I hope Your Highness will consider His Majesty's feelings.
Concubine Sourire,
will you walk to the yard yourself
or be carried by my servants?
Concubine Sourire,
please.
Imperial Mother, you don't look well.
You shouldn't exert your mind worrying about anything.
All you need is good rest.
I'm not exerting my mind to take care of the palace now.
Noble Consort Fleur is doing it at the
behest of the Emperor and the Empress.
Noble Consort Fleur has always assisted Her Majesty
as far back as when His Majesty was still a lord.
She will do well.
Don't worry, Imperial Mother.
But her temperament is just like her brother's.
They can do good deeds as well as bad ones.
Your Majesty, General Longkodo sent an ancient wild ginseng.
He wishes Your Majesty good health.
Yes.
Did you hear about what Noble Consort Fleur's brother did in court?
No wonder you don't feel well, Imperial Mother.
You have to follow the doctor's advice.
You have to stop worrying.
But here you are - worrying about the court.
Now that you've asked,
I will have to inquire into these things.
I'm fine with doing it once or twice.
But if this happens every time,
I won't want to visit the palace again.
You have a way with words.
I deserve to be punished for my offence.
But it will harm the imperial heir if I kneel for a long duration.
I hope Your Highness will reconsider.
Who do you think you are fooling?
You've always been well and have passed the first trimester.
Your pregnancy is stable now.
I've consulted the doctors.
It will be fine for a pregnant concubine to kneel - even for two hours.
- What are you doing?
- Kneel.
No. Stop!
My Lady.
I bear the punishment because Your Noble Highness
acts on behalf of Their Majesties.
But justice is in everyone's heart
and not imposed by punishment.
Very well. I will let you know
whether justice is in my hands
or in your heart.
Read it aloud.
Until I'm satisfied.
Concubine Sourire is pregnant and shouldn't be kneeling.
Does pregnancy convey exemption from the rules of the palace?
Have you forgotten your own lesson?
Now that you intercede for her,
you are allowed to kneel with her.
Lady Vertu wasn't interceding for me.
I hope Your Highness will not punish her for my own failure.
What if I want to punish her for your offence?
Since you two are like sisters,
she will kneel down and read next to you.
So she will also learn the "rules".
I'm here with you.
It's terribly hot.
Bring chairs here for all the concubines.
So they can observe how defiant concubines are punished.
Even the sweat of beautiful women smells unpleasant.
- Songzhi
- Yes
Bring out the censer.
My Pleasancy incense will remove the odor.
Yes.
"I was beloved by my late husband for the
good teachings of my mother and teacher."
"I remarried at age fourteen into the Cao family
and became their humble servant."
"Although forty years have passed,"
"I still tremble with fear,
afraid of offending my husband's family,"
"hoping not to bring dishonor to my parents and family."
"I worked hard day and night
without asking for anything in return"
"From then on ..."
Your Noble Highness!
Kneeling for one hour won't kill her.
If you dare speak one more word,
you will kneel there with her.
You are not allowed to enter.
My Lady has been kneeling for so long.
Why don't they let her rise?
You know how Her Noble Highness is.
She is not yet ready to relent.
"I'm no longer worried about the boys
who are able to support themselves."
Stop!
I'm from the Palace of Pearl Jade.
I urgently ask to see Her Majesty.
Her Majesty is unwell.
She is sleeping after her medicine.
Don't you dare disturb Her Majesty!
It's a matter of life and death. Please let me go in.
You won't be able to see Her Majesty even if I let you in.
And if you disturb Her Majesty,
it won't matter how many lives you save.
Your Majesty!
Leave!
If you were not from the Palace of Pearl Jade, we would
have already sent you to the.Department of Penalty
Go!
Jade, what brings you here?
Ajin, why are you here?
Me? Why can't I be here?
I came with His Lordship.
Ajin, where is His Lordship?
“Section One: Humbleness and Obedience ..."
"In ancient times, female infants were
placed under the bed when three days old."
"Spindles and bricks were laid next to them
to announce their births to the ancestors."
- Zhou Ninghai.
- Yes.
Beat them.
Beat the one that's not pregnant instead.
Yes.
Don't beat her!
Watch out, My Lady!
- Watch out, My Lady!
- You can't beat her!
My Lady!
Your Noble Highness!
If you are caught being flippant again,
your good sister will take the punishment for you.
Your Noble Highness,
I am truly feeling unwell.
Everyone, look at her making a fool of herself.
She is feigning sickness the way Lady Fuca did.
Doesn't she know it's bothersome to hear
the same excuse over and over again?
Why don't you try something new?
Your Noble Highness, Sourire is feeling weak.
If she faints from heatstroke,
I’m afraid Your Highness won't be able to escape the blame.
I need to see whether she will faint or not.
Zhou Ninghai.
- Burn some mint and mugwort leaves.
- Yes.
If she still faints from heatstroke,
I will consider that a deception.
Even if I can't punish you directly,
I will not spare Lady Vertu and Attendant An,
who are party to your corrupt ways.
"Section Two: Principles of Husband and Wife."
"Husband and wife follow the principles of Yin and Yang"
"which applies to all gods of Heaven and Earth,
and emcompasses their great Tao"
"and the moral ethics."
I beg Your Noble Highness to forgive her.
Please forgive her!
Your Noble Highness!
"This is why Guanju is the first poem listed in the Book of Songs."
"From these,"
"we know we must obey the Principles of Husband and Wife."
"An unvirtuous husband can not command his wife ..."
Your Highness, it's been an hour already.
No hurry. She will kneel for another quarter hour.
I'm afraid if something happens to her,
The blame on Your Noble Highness will be unbearable!
Your Highness, Concubine Sourire already looks pale.
Is she making this disingenuous display for my benefit?
She looks perfectly well to me.
My Lady.
-Huan'er.
-My Lady.
Huan'er!
-Huan'er!
-My Lady!
-Huan'er, are you all right?
-Huan'er!
--My Lady!
Out of my way.
Get out of my way!
Huan'er!
My Lady!
Noble Prince Guo.
My Lady, are you all right?
Quick.
How dare you intrude into the Palace of Earthly Honor?
Stop! Where are you taking her?
Don't you know it is a capital offense to
intrude into His Majesty's harem?
The offense will be determined by His Majesty.
I am here to protect the imperial heir.
If I receive punishment for what I do today,
at least my conscience won't be guilty.
Stop!
Your Highness! Your Highness!
There seems to be blood on the ground.
How could this happen?
It has only been an hour.
How can she be bleeding?
Send for the doctor!
What happened?
Careful.
Blanket, the blanket.
My Lady ...
Concubine Sourire ...
-My Lady.
-What happened?
-What should we do?
-Help her get changed.
Go quickly.
You go get water!
And you call for the doctors! Be quick!
Your Lordship,
His Majesty and Her Majesty are at the
Temple of Heaven and we cannot leave the palace.
We can only count on Your Lordship to bring His Majesty back.
Your Lordship.
It is not appropriate for Your Lordship to be here.
Your Lordship should leave.
My Lady.
I thank Your Lordship.
Your Lordship.
I thank Your Lordship for rescuing My Lady.
Concubine Sourire ...
You must take good care of her.
When Your Lordship reports to His Majesty,
please tell every detail of
what happened at the Palace of Earthly Honor.
I will tell His Majesty every single detail.
My Lady.
His Majesty's harem lacks peace and harmony
and His Majesty is in need of more heirs.
I plead for Heaven's blessings.
Please help Concubine Sourire safely give birth to a prince.
Heaven will respond to your kindness.
My wish was that Concubine Sourire
will give birth to a prince.
This will expand the imperial family
and the Third Prince will have another younger brother.
Speaking of the Third Prince,
although he has two younger brothers,
they both live outside the palace and
the Third Prince might feel lonely.
I'm glad to hear that their Imperial Mother
cares so much about them.
I was incompetent.
I failed to take care of the First Prince.
And my sister passed away
while giving birth to the Second Prince.
We did not receive Heaven's blessings to raise imperial heirs.
I only hope the other concubines
will soon "branch out the family".
You are a virtuous Empress.
That's Heaven's blessing for me.
Your Majesty... Your Majesty.
What happened?
Your Majesty.
There was an accident at the Palace of Pearl Jade.
What happened to Concubine Sourire?
Just a moment, Your Majesty.
Lord XVII will come here and report to Your Majesty.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.